Guide to the John W. Spencer Nature Study papers, 1897-1912.
Spencer, John W. Nature Study papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
John W. Spencer Nature Study papers, 1897-1912.
21-24-238
John W. Spencer
2 cubic feet
Correspondence and memorabilia.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence about nature study leaflets, agricultural problems, including some with members of the state legislature and some personal correspondence.
Also, an engraved silver goblet given to Mr. and Mrs. John Walton Spencer, June 11-12, 1912.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Deputy Chief of Extension Work, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence about nature study leaflets, agricultural problems, including some with members of the state legislature and some personal correspondence.
Also, an engraved silver goblet given to Mr. and Mrs. John Walton Spencer, June 11-12, 1912.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Spencer, John W.; Rensselaer, Martha Van, 1864-1932; Comstock, Anna Botsford, 1854-1930; Comstock, J. Henry (John Henry), 1849-1931 LH Bailey; Bailey, Liberty Hyde, 1858-1954; Cornell University. Extension Work.; Cornell University -- Faculty.; Cornell University
Subjects:
Universities and colleges -- Faculty
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence
  Correspondence sent to John W. Spencer, primarily requesting Nature Leaflet reports, from schoolchildren, teachers and other educators. A small number of letters are more personal in nature.
  - January - October 1897, 1897-01-01-1897-10-30; 34 pieces (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - November 1897, 1897-11-01-1897-11-09; 29 pieces (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - November 1897, 1897-11-10-1897-11-17; 29 pieces (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - November 1897, 1897-11-17-1897-11-26; 30 pieces (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - November 1897, 1897-11-26-1897-11-30; 29 pieces (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - December 1897, 1897-12-01-1897-12-07; 32 pieces (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - December 1897, 1897-12-07-1897-12-11; 26 pieces (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - December 1897, 1897-12-11-1897-12-15; 26 pieces (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - December 1897, 1897-12-16-1897-12-22; 25 pieces (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - December 1897, 1897-12-22-1897-12-31; 35 pieces (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - January 1898, 1898-01-01-1898-01-06; 25 pieces (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - January 1898, 1898-01-06-1898-01-14; 28 pieces (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Includes letter inquiring whether John Spencer is related to other Spencers in the state; also a letter from his cousin Edgar A. Spencer.
  - January 1898, 1898-01-14-1898-01-24; 27 pieces (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - January 1898, 1898-01-24-1898-01-31; 39 pieces (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Includes letter describing the plight of farmers in society (Jan 28).
  - February 1898, 1898-02-01-1898-02-07; 25 pieces (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - February 1898, 1898-02-07-1898-02-11; 31 pieces (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - February 1898, 1898-02-16-1898-02-16; 26 pieces (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Includes letters from Anna Comstock, J. H. Comstock, Martha Van Rensselaer.
  - February 1898, 1898-02-16-1898-02-25; 30 pieces (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Includes letter from Martha Van Rensselaer
  - February 1898, 1898-02-25-1898-02-28; 21 pieces (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Includes letter from Anna Comstock
  - March 1898, 1898-03-01-1898-03-07; 25 pieces (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Includes letter signed "Comstock", probably J.H.
  - March 1898, 1898-03-08-1898-03-15 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Includes letter from a teacher (Jackson) at Tuskagee Normal and Industrial Institute during the period when Booker T. Washington was Principal.
  - March 1898, 1898-03-16-1898-03-21; 23 pieces (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Includes telegram from Albany, "Bill signed today" re: Nixon Bill.
  - March 1898, 1898-03-22-1898-03-26; 30 pieces (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Includes letter from his Cousin; Includes letter from Martha Van Renssalaer
  - March 1898, 1898-03-26-1898-03-30; 24 pieces (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - March 1898, 1898-03-31; 13 pieces (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Includes passenger list for American Line sailing from NY to Southampton, with LH Bailey listed as passenger.
  - April 1898, 1898-04-01-1898-04-05; 29 pieces (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Includes brief letter from LH Bailey in Strasbourg regarding edits to manuscript.
  - April 1898, 1898-04-06-1898-04-13; 28 pieces (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - April 1898, 1898-04-15-1898-04-30; 30 pieces (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Includes letter from G. W. Carver when Director of Tuskagee Normal and Industrial Institute
  - April 1898, 1898-04-16-1898-04-19; 28 pieces (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - April 1898, 1898-04-19-1898-04-21; 29 pieces (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - April 1898, 1898-04-22-1898-04-25; 32 pieces (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - April 1898, 1898-04-26-1898-04-29; 26 pieces (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - April 1898, 1898-04-29-1898-04-30; 24 pieces (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - May 1898, 1898-05-01-1898-05-03; 20 pieces (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - May 1898, 1898-05-03-1898-05-05; 33 pieces (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - May 1898, 1898-05-06-1898-05-09; 29 pieces (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - May 1898, 1898-05-09-1898-05-12; 30 pieces (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - May 1898, 1898-05-12-1898-05-16; 26 pieces (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Includes Spencer's response to earlier letter regarding family geneaology (in 1-12)
  - May 1898, 1898-05-16-1898-05-19; 30 pieces (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - May 1898, 1898-05-19-1898-05-23; 30 pieces (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - May 1898, 1898-05-23-1898-05-25; 29 pieces (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - May 1898, 1898-05-05-1898-05-26; 36 pieces (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - May 1898, 1898-05-27-1898-05-29; 29 pieces (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - May 1898, 1898-05-29-1898-05-31; 30 pieces (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Includes responsefrom a teacher (Jackson) at Tuskagee Normal and Industrial Institute during the period when Booker T. Washington was Principal.
  - June 1898, 1898-06-01-1898-06-02; 28 pieces (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - June 1898, 1898-06-02-1898-06-04; 28 pieces (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - June 1898, 1898-06-05-1898-06-07; 30 pieces (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - June 1898, 1898-06-07-1898-06-10; 28 pieces (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - June 1898, 1898-06-10-1898-06-13; 26 pieces (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - June 1898, 1898-06-14-1898-06-17; 32 pieces (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - June 1898, 1898-06-18-1898-06-21; 27 pieces (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - June 1898, 1898-06-22-1898-06-25; 30 pieces (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - June 1898, 1898-06-26-1898-06-28; 26 pieces (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - June 1898, 1898-06-28-1898-06-30; 17 pieces (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Includes a letter from his cousin.
  - July 1898, 1898-07-01-1898-07-10; 25 pieces (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - July 1898, 1898-07-11-1898-07-20; 27 pieces (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - July 1898, 1898-07-21-1898-07-31; 27 pieces (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Includes letter from a colleague in Paris commenting on the French army; includes composition by an 18 yr old still in school entitled "The Future", commenting on many new inventions, the Spanish-Ameriacn war and imagining the future.
  - August 1898, 1898-08-01-1898-08-10; 23 pieces (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - August 1898, 1898-08-11-1898-08-19; 31 pieces (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - August 1898, 1898-08-22-1898-08-31; 32 pieces (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Includes letter from cousin Edgar Spencer.
  - September 1898, 1898-09-01-1898-09-08; 30 pieces (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - September 1898, 1898-09-08-1898-09-12; 28 pieces (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - September 1898, 1898-09-12-1898-09-14; 21 pieces (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - September 1898, 1898-09-15-1898-09-16; 22 pieces (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - September 1898, 1898-09-17-1898-09-20; 29 pieces (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - September 1898, 1898-09-20-1898-09-23; 28 pieces (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - September 1898, 1898-09-23-1898-09-25; 27 pieces (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - September 1898, 1898-09-26-1898-09-27; 31 pieces (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - September 1898, 1898-09-28-1898-09-30; 31 pieces (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - October 1898, 1898-10-01-1898-10-03; 29 pieces (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - October 1898, 1898-10-03-1898-10-05; 27 pieces (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - October 1898, 1898-10-06-1898-10-08; 27 pieces (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - October 1898, 1898-10-08-1898-10-11; 26 pieces (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Includes clipping from "Primary Education" journal about the Bureau of Nature Study".
  - October 1898, 1898-10-11-1898-10-13; 28 pieces (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - October 1898, 1898-10-13-1898-10-14; 27 pieces (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - October 1898, 1898-10-15-1898-10-17; 28 pieces (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - October 1898, 1898-10-17-1898-10-20; 26 pieces (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - October 1898, 1898-10-20-1898-10-22; 25 pieces (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - October 1898, 1898-10-23-1898-10-24; 25 pieces (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - October 1898, 1898-10-25-1898-10-27; 23 pieces (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - October 1898, 1898-10-27-1898-10-31; 26 pieces (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - October 1898, 1898-10-31-Undated; 28 pieces (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Includes a request on postcard for nature leaflets from a teacher in Russia.
  - November 1898, 1898-11-01-1898-11-03; 28 pieces (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - November 1898, 1898-11-03-1898-11-07; 25 pieces (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - November 1898, 1898-11-07-1898-11-09; 26 pieces (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - November 1898, 1898-11-10-1898-11-13; 26 pieces (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - November 1898, 1898-11-14-1898-11-15; 28 pieces (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - November 1898, 1898-11-15-1898-11-17; 29 pieces (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - November 1898, 1898-11-17-1898-11-19; 28 pieces (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - November 1898, 1898-11-19-1898-11-21; 30 pieces (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Includes letter from Alice Donlevy, Ladies Art Association of NY, with comments on the usefulness of various leaflets.
  - November 1898, 1898-11-21-1898-11-23; 25 pieces (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - November 1898, 1898-11-26-1898-11-29; 23 pieces (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - November 1898, 1898-11-29-1898-11-30; 22 pieces (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - December 1898, 1898-12-01-1898-12-03; 24 pieces (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Includes letter from Martha Van Rensselaer.
  - December 1898, 1898-12-04-1898-12-07; 27 pieces (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - December 1898, 1898-12-07-1898-12-12; 26 pieces (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - December 1898, 1898-12-13-1898-12-16; 27 pieces (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - December 1898, 1898-12-16-1898-12-21; 24 pieces (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - December 1898, 1898-12-21-1898-12-26; 26 pieces (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - December 1898, 1898-12-26-1898-12-30; 28 pieces (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Includes letter from Anna Comstock about manuscript for chicken leaflet
  - December 1898, 1898-12-30-1898-12-31; 20 pieces (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - January 1899, 1899-01-01-1899-01-27; 16 pieces (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - January 1899, 1899-01-28-1899-01-31; 8 pieces (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - February 1899, 1899-02-01-1899-02-13; 18 pieces (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - February 1899, 1899-02-14-1899-02-18; 27 pieces (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - February 1899, 1899-02-19-1899-02-21; 27 pieces (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - February 1899, 1899-02-22-1899-02-23; 27 pieces (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - February 1899, 1899-02-24-1899-02-25; 28 pieces (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Includes letter from Ernest Ingersoll.
  - February 1899, 1899-02-25-1899-02-27; 23 pieces (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - February 1899, 1899-02-27-1899-02-28; 22 pieces (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - March 1899, 1899-03-01-1899-03-03; 28 pieces (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - March 1899, 1899-03-04-1899-03-06; 26 pieces (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - March 1899, 1899-03-06-1899-03-07; 26 pieces (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - March 1899, 1899-03-07-1899-03-09; 29 pieces (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - March 1899, 1899-03-09-1899-03-13; 26 pieces (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - March 1899, 1899-03-13-1899-03-14; 24 pieces (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - March 1899, 1899-03-14-1899-03-15; 24 pieces (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - March 1899, 1899-03-16-1899-03-18; 27 pieces (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - March 1899, 1899-03-18-1899-03-20; 25 pieces (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - March 1899, 1899-03-20-1899-03-22; 27 pieces (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - March 1899, 1899-03-23-1899-03-25; 25 pieces (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - March 1899, 1899-03-25-1899-03-27; 24 pieces (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - March 1899, 1899-03-23-1899-03-29; 23 pieces (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - March 1899, 1899-03-19-1899-03-31; 23 pieces (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - March 1899, 1899-03; 16 pieces (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - April 1899, 1899-04-01-1899-04-03; 25 pieces (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - April 1899, 1899-04-03-1899-04-06; 26 pieces (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - April 1899, 1899-04-07-1899-04-08; 23 pieces (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Includes a letter discussing photography
  - April 1899, 1899-04-09-1899-04-30; 27 pieces (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - May 1899, 1899-05-01-1899-05-16; 20 pieces (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - May 1899, 1899-05-18-1899-05-19; 24 pieces (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - May 1899, 1899-05-16-1899-05-17; 24 pieces (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - May 1899, 1899-05-19-1899-05-21; 23 pieces (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - May and June 1899, 1899-05-1899-06-30; 15 pieces (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - May 1899, 1899-05-22-1899-05-23; 27 pieces (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - May 1899, 1899-05-23-1899-05-24; 30 pieces (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - May 1899, 1899-05-25-1899-05-26; 25 pieces (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - May 1899, 1899-05-26-1899-05-29; 24 pieces (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - May 1899, 1899-05-29-1899-05-30; 23 pieces (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - May 1899, 1899-05-31; 18 pieces (Box 5, Folder 33)